Guide to the Joe Jeff Goldblatt Papers, 1984-1997 MS2063
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Special Events: The Art and Science of Celebration, 1988-1990; MS2063 Series 1; 3 Linear feet
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption for photograph 12, bride's walk down the aisle, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption for photograph 2, "Ken" in balloons, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption for photograph 3, balloons in atrium over piano player, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Photocopy proof of black and white photograph section, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption of ice-carving of duck, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption of violin players on stairs and staff with trays, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption of theme band, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Oversize: Photographs and Figures: Color print and draft caption of Allison--Bat Mitzvah, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Louis Vitelli; [unidentified], undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: [damaged], undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Eugene H. Dibble, president of Reach Enterprises Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Hugh Hunt, Hugh Hunt Productions; Convention Service Management- Geoffery P. Dirckson, Alvin Brazile, Jr., Steve Schwartz, Cathy Seary, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Convention Service Management- Geoffery P. Dirckson, Alvin Brazile, Jr., Steve Schwartz, Cathy Seary, (continued from tape 4), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: John P. Brooke-Little, King of Arms; Peter Stiles, TXP, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Howard Zusel, A-1 Enterprises Inc.; Thomas W. Gallagher, Command Performance, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Thomas P. Gallagher, Command Performance (continued from tape 7); John Golden, Western Costume; Sharon Siegel, Celebrations Party Design, Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Sharon Siegel, Celebrations Party Design, Inc. (continued from tape 8), undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Sharon Siegel, Celebrations Party Design, Inc. (continued from tape 8 and 9), undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: [unidentified]; Dawn M. Reed, Major, USAF; Mark Murray, special events officer for military district of Washington; Beatrice Canterbury Lavery, Mayor's Office of Protocol, Los Angeles, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Douglas M. Brenner, LaserMedia Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Douglas M. Brenner, LaserMedia Inc. (continued from tape 12), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Hal Etkin, Multi-Entertainment, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Raymond B. Thomposn, Images by Lighting, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: [damaged side A]; Jerry Levin, The Balloon Master Ltd.; Earl C. Hargrove and Chris Hargrove, Hargrove, Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Stanley Paul, Stanley Paul Orchestras, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Paul G. Demos; Ramona R. Ball; G. Eugene Wigger, Marriott's Harbor Beach Resort, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: G. Eugene Wigger, Marriott's Harbor Beach Resort (continued from tape 18), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Selwa S. Roosevelt, former Federal Chief of Protocol, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: [damaged], undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Gillian Holter, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Frank Supovitz, Radio City Music Hall; Wayne Stetson, National Association of Homebuilders; Laura Wallace, Coca-Cola, USA; Don Whiteley, Argonne Industries; Rita Bloom, Creative Parties, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Terry L. Brady, Brady Companies; Mona S. Meretsky, COMCOR; Audrey Gordon, Audrey Gordon Parties; Emmie S. Mikulay, Madison Square Garden; Burt Ferrini, Northeastern Illinois University, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Barnett Lipton, Eventures Inc.; Julie Loshin, Parties Plus, Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Cindy Girodano, Universal Studios, Hollywood, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Josette Locklar, NCA; Carol McKibben, Special Events magazine; Mike Davies, Disneyland Hotel, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Lester Lanin, musical director; Arnold H. Saltzman, Cantor; Eugene Donati, musical director, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Michael H. Macrae, Harrod's; Grace Cheung, Royal Lancaster Hotel, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Moshen Amer and Michael Reed, Royal Lancaster Hotel, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Dan Hnatio, Active Video, Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Ed Jones, pregame producer, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Jack Morton, Jack Morton Productions, Inc., undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Mary Midkiff, American Horse Council; misc. musical selections, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: "Johnathon" and Betty Haig, Old Swan Hotel; "Peter", Hotel St. James, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Naomi Rhode, describes wedding anniversary, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Carey Weiman, C.S. Productions; [unidentified], undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: "Hazel", P.J. Promotions; Roger de Pilkington, Payne and Gunter Caterers; [unidentified], undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Elly Brewer, Edge of the Seat Productions; Alex McGiven, events director in London, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Bernard Sullivan, Toastmaster, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Freddie Meynell, Searcy's Catering; Sir Thomas Ingilby, heir to Ripley Castle, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Joel Tropper, Walt Disney World's Pleasure Island; Frank Dickson, Ray Bloch Productions, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: BBC Radio interview with Joe Jeff Goldblatt; Pat Fulton, convention speaker, trainer and management consultant; Judith Reddington, Homart Corporation, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Robert Jani, Walt Disney Company; Michael Jackson Concert, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Audiocassettes: Book Related: Misc. musical selections used in special events, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: International Special Events Society, Atlanta- "Mastering the Event Management & Marketing Process," David G. Wilkinson, 08/06/1988-08/10/1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: International Special Events Society, Atlanta- "The Most Important Memorable Events in Your Clients Life," Barbara Tober and Harriette Rose Katz, 08/06/1988-08/10/1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: International Special Events Society, Philadelphia- "Don't Spin Your Wheels: Creating a Win/Win Partnership,", 08/12/1990-08/15/1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: National Speakers Association (NSA)- "The Secrets of Power Negotiating,' Robert Dawson, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: NSA- "How Not to 'Step In It' When Speaking Internationally," Robert E. Johnson, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: NSA- Special Interest Group for Seminar/Workshop Leaders-Pt.II, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Fast Forward: Communication Skills for Future Success, Tape 1, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Fast Forward: Communication Skills for Future Success, Tape 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Fast Forward: Communication Skills for Future Success, Tape 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Safety, A Necessary Ingredient for Success, Tape 1, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Safety, A Necessary Ingredient for Success, Tape 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Scoring a Hit, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Risk Responsibility, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Time Power, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Promoting Your Creative Edge, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Get Yourself and Your Company Through the Legal Jungle, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Success in Special Events: A Short Cut to the Top, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Coordinating Events for Non-Profit Organizations, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Audiocassettes: Non-Book Related: Shifting Your Special Events Business into Second Gear, Tape 2 (Tape 1 is missing), undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Dictionary of Event Management, 1996; MS2063 Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains copy-edited manuscripts. These materials are dated 1996. This series consists of the complete copy-edited version of the Dictionary of Event Management, which is divided into two folders. The first folder contains the A through K part (first half) of the Dictionary, while the second folder houses the K through Z (last half). A third folder contains a dated, signed letter from a production assistant, introducing the "folded and gathered" version of the Dictionary, upon which Goldblatt could make final corrections.
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript, Chapters A-K, 02/01/1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript, Chapters K-Z, 02/01/1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Book Manuscript: "Folded and Gathered" Sheets, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Special Events: The Best Practices in Modern Event Management, 1996; MS2063 Series 3; 1 Linear feet
  This series contains copy-edited manuscripts, manuscript galleys, and photographs, slides, and illustrations. This material is dated 1996. This series consists of manuscript material for Goldblatt's book, "Special Events: The Best Practices in Modern Event Management." This material includes all the parts of the book including: text, title page, table of contents, forward, preface, acknowledgments (folder ), appendices (folders ), and figures. Also included are three photographs depicting prominent events such as the 23rd summer Olympics in Los Angeles, California.
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Title page-acknowledgments, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 1, Introduction to Event Management, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 2, The Five Critical Stages for all Successful Events, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 3, Designing the Event Environment, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 4, Financial Techniques for Consistent Success, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 5, Quality Event Leadership for Staff and Volunteers, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 6, The Production Schedule, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 7, Effective Catering Techniques, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 8, Audio-Visual, Lighting, Sound, Special Effects, and Video, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 9, Music and Entertainment, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 10, Integrated Marketing, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 11, Sponsorship, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 12, Cause Related Events, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 13, Contracts, Permits, Licenses, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 14, Risk Management Procedures, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 15, Ethics, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Chapter 16, Epilogue, 03/12/1996 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Appendices 1-3, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Appendices 4-12, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Book Manuscript: Copy-Edited Manuscript: Figures, 02/13/1996 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Title page-acknowledgments, 10/17/1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 1, Introduction to Event Management, 09/23/1996-09/26/1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 2, The Five Critical Stages for All Successful Events, 09/23/1996-09/24/1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 3, Designing the Event Environment, 09/26/1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 4, Financial Techniques for Consistent Success, 09/27/1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 5, Quality Event Leadership for Staff and Volunteers, 09/27/1996-09/30/1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 6, The Production Schedule, 09/30/1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 7, Effective Catering Techniques, 09/30/1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 8, Audiovisual, Lighting, Sound, Special Effects and Video, 10/01/1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 9, Music and Entertainment, 10/03/1996 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 10, Integrated Marketing, 10/07/1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 11, Sponsorship, 10/07/1996 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 12, Cause Related Events, 10/08/1996 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 13, Contracts, Permits, and Licenses, 10/08/1996 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 14, Risk Management Procedures, 10/09/1996 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 15, Ethics, 10/10/1996-10/11/1996 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Chapter 16, Epilogue, 10/11/1996 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Appendices 1-3, 10/11/1996 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Book Manuscript: Manuscript Galleys: Appendices 4-12, 10/11/1996 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Photographs and Figures: Figures 1.1-1.16, 1986-1995 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Photographs and Figures: Figures 2.1-2.14, 1974-1995 (Box 10, Folder 21)